### Mariah C. Boudreau, Ph.D.

(802) 582-9854 | mariahcecileboudreau@gmail.com | mariahcboudreau.github.io

#### **Professional Summary**

An organized and enthusiastic computational scientist with 5 years of experience in stochastic modeling and simulations. I am eager to work on complex research questions that leverage computational methods, particularly questions corresponding to the sexual and reproductive health of individuals living in diverse environments.

Education	Skills
University of Vermont   Burlington, VT Aug. 2019 - Aug. 2024 Ph.D. in Mathematical Sciences	<b>Coding:</b> Python (numpy, pandas, matplotlib, geopandas), parallelization, Git, LaTeX, RStudio, SQL.
Saint Michael's College   Colchester, VT Aug. 2015 - May 2019 B.S. in Mathematics Minors in Computer Science and Statistics	<b>Technical material:</b> Probability theory, Statistical analysis (linear and logistic regression), Branching process theory, Stochastic simulations, Machine learning techniques.
Work Experience	

work Experience

**Postdoctoral Researcher** | The Roux Institute at Northeastern University, Portland, ME

Sept. 2024 - Present

- Constructing Python workflows for airline travel network database cleaning and surveillance optimization on this network.
- Extending this workflow to include global surveillance optimization for high-risk spillover regions.
- Collaborating with the CDC on optimizing disease surveillance systems in the US.
- Prepared global maps of disease detection for specific surveillance locations to showcase the capabilities of our analysis for a presentation with collaborators.
- Established a postdoctoral researcher affinity group to connect this community within the Roux research vertical.

### Ph.D. Candidate | University of Vermont, Burlington, VT

Aug. 2019 - Aug. 2024

- Conducted research addressing uncertainties in within-host and population-level disease dynamics for my dissertation.
- Developed a mechanistic model using master equations to estimate human papillomavirus (HPV) viral load parameters for a population-level model.
- Extended a time-dependent probability generating function model to incorporate two intervention strategies, and concisely conveyed the results with four intervention comparison metrics.
- Presented chapters of my dissertation research at two conferences.

- Processed blood work and health history survey data for the Lived Experience Measured Using Rings Study.
- Performed a regression analysis to understand the relationship between an individual's blood work and their OURA Ring Gen3 sleep data, segmented by their history of chronic conditions.

**Contractor** | Institute for Disease Modeling at the Gates Foundation, Seattle, WA May 2022 - July 2022

- Assisted in parameterizing and developing an open-source HPV population model with the Computational Science Research group.
- Studied the agent-based model framework developed at the Institute for Disease Modeling.
- Studied the disease progression of HPV in an individual to inform mechanistic model dynamics.
- Collaborated with HPV experts and clinicians.
- Participated in brainstorming and strategic planning meetings to understand the role of projects in the foundation's goals.

## **Technical Services Intern** | Mylan Technologies, Saint Albans, VT June 2019 - Aug. 2019

 Analyzed sampling, a mass balance, and other essential functions of transdermal production at the Mylan Technologies Saint Albans manufacturing plant to highlight inefficiencies.

#### Publications and other writings

#### M.C. Boudreau, J.A. Cohen, & L. Hébert-Dufresne

Within-host infection dynamics with master equations and the method of moments: A case study of human papillomavirus in the epithelium

ArXiv (currently under peer review)

R.M. Stuart, J.A. Cohen, C.C. Kerr, P. Mathur, R.G. Abeysuriya, M. Zimmerman, D.W. Rao, **M.C. Boudreau**, S. Lee, L. Yang, & D.J. Klein

*HPVsim: An agent-based model of HPV transmission and cervical disease* PLOS Comput. Biol. 20(7) e1012181

# **M.C. Boudreau**, A.J. Allen, N.J. Roberts, A. Allard, & L. Hébert-Dufresne *Temporal and probabilistic comparisons of epidemic interventions* Bull. of Math. Biol. 85(12), 118

# A.J. Allen, **M.C. Boudreau**, N.J. Roberts, A. Allard, & L. Hébert-Dufresne *Predicting the diversity of early epidemic spread on networks*Phys. Rev. Research 4, 013123

#### **Interests**

Volunteer work: Ski patrol, Mount Otto Rhode Race volunteer